hello welcome welcome
你好 欢迎 欢迎
this is going to be my first video on
这将是我的第一个视频
dark table
暗桌
i wanted to make a shortish introduction
我想做个简短的介绍
video that i could reference in the
视频 我可以在
future
未来
so what we are going to do today is
所以我们今天要做的是
touch on the very important core basics
触及非常重要的核心基础
of dark table and we are going to
一张黑桌 我们要去
process a photo from start to finish
从头到尾处理一张照片
using scene repaired workflow
使用场景修复工作流
so you've installed dark table and
所以你安装了暗桌和
launched it for the first time
它是第一次推出
of course the first thing we are going
当然 我们要做的第一件事是
to do
去做
is change some settings
就是更改一些设置
let's go to preferences
让我们转到首选项
processing
正在处理中
and make sure auto apply pixel workflow
并确保自动应用像素工作流
defaults are set to scene referred and
默认设置为参考场景和
auto apply chromatic adaptation defaults
自动应用色调调整默认值
are set to modern
都被设置成现代的
that's that we can close this window
那就是我们可以关闭这扇窗
now this interface might be familiar to
现在 您可能对此界面很熟悉
some of you especially to people coming
你们中的一些人 尤其是来到这里的人
from adobe lightroom
来自Adobe Lightroom
i will try my best to avoid the direct
我会尽我所能避免直接
comparison in this video
此视频中的比较
but as a former lightroom user myself i
但作为Lightroom的前用户 我
might mislabel a thing or two here and
可能会在这里贴错一两个标签 然后
there doc table consists of a couple of
那里的文件表由几个
main sections light table and dark room
主要部分：亮桌子和暗房间
there are others but they're not going
还有其他人 但他们不去
to touch these today
今天去触摸这些
currently we're in the light table
目前我们正坐在轻桌上
section where we can manage our photos
我们可以在那里管理我们的照片
and collections the darkroom section is
和收藏品暗房部分是
purely for developing photos
纯粹是为了冲洗照片
let's start at the beginning
让我们从头开始吧
let's say i've already copied a couple
比方说我已经复制了几份
of photos from my sd card in a dedicated
我的SD卡中的照片放在一个专用的
folder somewhere on my computer what i
我电脑上某处的文件夹我
need to do is import them into dark
需要做的就是将它们导入黑暗中
table expand the import section and
表展开导入部分和
click add to library
单击添加到库
simply navigate to the folder where you
只需导航到您要在其中
copied your photos or click the plus
复制您的照片或单击加号
sign if it's not in the list of places
如果它不在地点列表中 请签名
already
已经
awesome these are my photos i will tick
太棒了 这些是我的照片 我会打勾的
the ignore jpeg images box as i have no
忽略jpeg图像框 因为我没有
use for them
为他们使用
i will click the select new button which
我将单击选择新按钮 该按钮
will only add photos that are not
将仅添加未添加的照片
currently in the album
目前在专辑中
this way we can quickly and easily top
通过这种方式 我们可以快速轻松地超越
up any existing album also known as
升级任何现有的专辑 也称为
collection with new photos
带新照片的收藏
you can also preview the photos by
您也可以通过以下方式预览照片
clicking on the eye icon
点击眼睛图标
finally let's hit the add library button
最后 让我们点击添加库按钮
let's select an image we want to work on
让我们选择一个我们想要处理的图像
and let's go to the dark room
让我们去黑暗的房间
we'll quickly gloss over the workflow of
我们将快速介绍以下工作流程
developing a photo as it's slightly
冲洗照片 因为它略微
different than in other photography
与其他摄影不同
software packages just because in dark
软件包 只是因为在黑暗中
table you have the complete control of
您可以完全控制的表
developing process and image pipeline
显影流程和图像流水线
on the right you will notice a list of
在右侧 您会注意到一个列表
familiar terms
熟悉的术语
these are called modules there are a few
这些被称为模块 有几个
mandatory modules most of them you can
必修模块--大多数都可以
enable and disable
启用和禁用
duplicate
复本
reset
重置
or store a preset off and most
或存储预置关闭和最大
importantly move but let's not make a
重要的是搬家 但我们不要
mess just yet and leave it in the
一团糟 然后把它留在
default order
默认顺序
the order is important as the modules
顺序很重要 因为模块
are processed from the bottom up it
都是自下而上处理的
means that it will adjust the raw black
意味着它将调整原始黑色
white point first then move to white
先用白点 然后移到白色
balance then highlight reconstruction so
平衡然后突出显示重建 以便
on and so forth since we're using
等等 因为我们正在使用
scenery fed workflow let's switch to a
场景馈送的工作流程让我们切换到
predefined scene referred modules and
预定义的场景参考模块和
module ordering
模块排序
this will get rid of all the deprecated
这将消除所有不推荐使用的
and display referred modules that we
并显示我们引用的模块
can't really use in our pipeline
在我们的管道中不能真正使用
at the top here you can currently see
在这里的顶部 您当前可以看到
six tabs
六个选项卡
we can modify these in preferences but
我们可以在首选项中修改这些设置 但是
let's work with what we have for now
让我们利用目前已有的资源
the first one is quick settings which
第一个是快速设置 它
i'm not a big fan of so let's go
我不太喜欢 所以我们走吧
straight to tab 2
直接转到选项卡2
which contains either active modules or
它包含活动模块或
all available modules
所有可用模块
we can switch between these two modes by
我们可以通过以下方式在这两种模式之间切换
using the tab button like a toggle
像切换一样使用制表符按钮
active all
全部激活
active
主动型
all
全
the third tab is responsible for the
第三个选项卡负责
core of the image and it's called base
图像的核心 它被称为底座
we can tweak the rotation adjust the
我们可以调整旋转 调整
exposure
暴露
and most importantly use the filmic rgb
最重要的是使用电影RGB
to transform our scene into something
把我们的场景变成某种东西
that can be viewed on a screen
可以在屏幕上查看的内容
next up is color which is
接下来是颜色 这是
self-explanatory
不言而喻
then image corrections and lastly
然后是图像校正 最后是
effects
效果
i always find myself using the active
我总是发现自己在使用活跃的
modules tab the most in tandem with the
模块选项卡与
search bar i think it's easier quicker
搜索栏我觉得更容易更快
and more intuitive
更直观
but it takes a bit of time to remember
但这需要一点时间才能记住
all the module names
所有模块名称
luckily they're pretty self-explanatory
幸运的是 它们是不言而喻的
right let's get to it
好的 让我们开始吧
first things first let's fix the glaring
最重要的是 让我们先解决这个问题
problems
问题
see this flat pancake of the sun with a
看这片平坦的太阳薄饼
bit of red this yellow drizzled around
这黄色的点点红色细雨洒在周围
it now i made this shot the way i made
现在我用我的方式拍了这张照片
it on purpose
它是故意的
it was really hot really sunny spring
春天真的很热很晴朗
day and i really wanted to portray that
我真的很想把它描绘出来
in the photo so including the entire
在照片中 所以包括整个
sign in the picture and overexposing was
在照片上签名 过度曝光是
an excellent decision
一个很好的决定
let's see if we can fix it we'll start
让我们看看能不能修好 我们就开始吧
by disabling the highlight
通过禁用高亮显示
reconstruction module as we will take
重建模块 因为我们将采取
care of the highlights later on
稍后关注亮点
firstly i will adjust the exposure
首先 我会调整曝光
slightly
略微
some parts of the image are still a bit
图像的某些部分仍然有一点
dark
黑暗
let's open the module
让我们打开模块
and we can make the adjustments simply
我们可以简单地进行调整
by clicking and dragging on the slider
通过在滑块上单击并拖动
hovering over and using a mouse wheel
在鼠标滚轮上悬停并使用鼠标滚轮
right clicking and making fine
单击鼠标右键并使其精细
adjustments
调整
or simply typing a number
或者简单地输入一个数字
that looks about right we can now close
看起来差不多了 我们现在可以关门了
the module next up color calibration
下一步是色彩校准模块
color calibration deals with the core
颜色校准涉及到核心
colors of the image mainly we will use
我们将主要使用图像的颜色
the color calibration to correctly set
要正确设置的颜色校准
the scene illuminant and adjust the
场景照明并调整
temperature
温度
you might notice that there is another
你可能会注意到还有另一个
module called white balance
称为白平衡的模块
don't touch that it's currently required
不要碰它当前需要的内容
for the color calibration module to work
要使颜色校准模块正常工作
correctly
正确无误
right so my eyes say that the image was
对 所以我的眼睛告诉我这张照片是
shot outside in a nice and sunny day we
在一个阳光明媚的日子里 我们在户外拍摄
can set the illuminant to d daylight
可以将光源设置为%d个日光
and adjust the temperature to our taste
并根据我们的口味调整温度
that's that
就是这样
let's move to my favorite module
让我们转到我最喜欢的模块
filmic rgb filmic rgb will help us take
电影RGB电影RGB将帮助我们
all the scene information we captured
我们捕捉到的所有现场信息
with our camera and compress it into
用我们的相机把它压缩成
something that our displays can
我们的显示器可以显示的东西
display
显示
otherwise everything outside the
否则 一切都不是
display's range which is typically zero
显示器的范围通常为零
to one
一比一
would get clipped out and every flat
会被剪掉 每一套公寓
pancake sun would stay a flat pancake
煎饼太阳会停留在平坦的煎饼上
sun
太阳
now this might look scary but i promise
这看起来可能很吓人 但我保证
it's only somewhat scary in short this
简而言之 它只是有点吓人
is showing how our scene will be mapped
显示了我们的场景将如何映射
to our display
到我们的展台
if we turn the axis labels on it will be
如果我们打开轴标签 它将是
a bit easier to understand
更容易理解一点
so the darkest part of the scene we
所以场景中最黑暗的部分是我们
captured will be mapped to zero on our
捕获的将映射到我们的
displays
显示
and the brightest part to the maximum
把最亮的部分调到最大
luminance of our displays
我们显示器的亮度
the ev0 the middle gray of the scene
场景的中间灰色部分
will be mapped to 18
将映射到18
of our display's output
我们显示器的输出
this is because our perception of
这是因为我们对
lightness is not linear i wouldn't like
亮度不是线性的 我不喜欢
to get any deeper into this topic in
要更深入地了解这个主题 请参阅
this specific video but there are really
这个特别的视频 但真的有
good in-depth videos by aurelion pierre
Aurelion Pierre精彩的深度视频
the maker of filmic rgb module where he
电影RGB模块的制造商 他在那里
goes in depth about how our vision and
深入探讨我们的愿景和
the module itself works
该模块本身可以工作
i will link his channel in the
我会把他的频道链接到
description and you might find one or
描述 您可能会找到一个或
two video cards appearing in my videos
我的视频中出现两个视频卡
in the top right corner so the quickest
在右上角 所以最快的
way of getting these settings dialed in
拨入这些设置的方式
right is by entering the values of your
正确的方法是通过输入您的
light meter that you surely had at the
你肯定有一个测光表
time the photo was taken right all right
这张照片拍对了 好的
the second quickest and good enough
第二快 也足够好
method
方法
is to use the autotune helpers so i'll
是使用自动调谐助手 所以我将
start with a white relative exposure
从白色相对曝光开始
okay that looks good to me
好的 我觉得很好
and then black relative exposure which
然后是黑色相对曝光 它
is slightly off for my taste so i will
有点不符合我的口味 所以我会
just increase the dynamic range by
只需将动态范围增加
adjusting the black relative exposure
调整黑色相对曝光
a few stops
几站
like so
就像这样
next we need to get rid of the awful
下一步 我们需要摆脱可怕的
mess that is the sun and a bit of
乱七八糟的就是太阳和一点
overexposed c here in the corner
在角落里曝光过多的c
for that let's move to reconstruct tab
为此 让我们移动到重建选项卡
of filmic the reconstruct tab is aptly
胶片的重建标签恰如其分地
cold as we have no data what's in the
很冷 因为我们没有数据
flat pancake as the clipping happened at
当剪裁发生在
the sensor so we will try to do our best
所以我们会尽最大努力
to artistically get out of this sticky
从艺术上摆脱这种粘性
situation
形势
let's enable the threshold mask by
让我们通过以下方式启用阈值掩码
clicking on the mask button let's walk
点击面具按钮 让我们走一走
back the threshold until we see the
回到门槛 直到我们看到
clipped parts of the image
图像的剪裁部分
okay that looks about right
好的 看起来差不多对了
next up transition
下一个向上过渡
i prefer to adjust this slider until i
我更喜欢调整这个滑块 直到我
faintly begin to see objects that are
隐约地开始看到
not overexposed i find that gives me an
没有过度曝光我发现这给了我一个
overall smoother image
整体图像更平滑
with only a slight impact on realism
对现实主义只有轻微的影响
we can now disable the mask
我们现在可以禁用面具了
now for the reconstruction itself
现在是重建本身
we can choose how much texture we want
我们可以选择我们想要的纹理
to attempt to recover
试图恢复
i want
我想要
none in this photo i don't care about
这张照片里没有一个我不关心的
texture here
这里的纹理
bloom or reconstruct
绽放或重建
i like to keep that at zero for a mix of
我喜欢将其保持在零 以进行混合
both
两者都有
and lastly whether to fill the clipped
最后 是否填充已裁剪的
areas with color or to desaturate them
带颜色的区域或将其去饱和化
i usually go for almost full
我通常几乎是满员的
desaturation and as that is the behavior
降低饱和度 因为这是一种行为
of film and in my opinion that is the
在我看来 这是
best way to convey brightness
传达亮度的最佳方式
like so
就像这样
i think that looks much much better and
我认为这看起来好多了 而且
much more natural
更自然
no more hard edge around the sun no more
太阳周围不再有坚硬的边缘
ugly cyan and no more rat piss yellow
难看的青色 不再有老鼠尿黄色
time coined by troy sobotka and frankly
时间由特洛伊·索博特卡创造 坦率地说
i can't stop using it
我不能停止使用它
right all we have to do now is
好的 我们现在要做的就是
straighten the horizon and bring back
拉直地平线 带回
some of the color into the image we can
我们可以把一些颜色加入到图像中
do that very quickly just type in
快速操作 只需键入即可
rotation in the search bar expand the
在搜索栏中旋转展开
rotate and perspective module and simply
旋转和透视模块 只需
right click and drag on something that
右击并拖动到某物上
should be perfectly straight
应该是完全笔直的
click the horizon
点击地平线
done and done
完成了 完成了
next up color
下一个颜色
for color always use color
对于颜色 请始终使用颜色
balance
平衡
rgb
RGB
it's also made by aurelie and pierre so
它也是由Aurele和Pierre So制作的
we are absolutely sure it plays nice
我们绝对肯定它会玩得很好
with filmic rgb
使用胶片RGB
again i will not get into detail in this
我再说一次 我不会在这件事上细说
video i'm just going to increase the
视频我只是要增加
global vibrance which will increase the
全球活力 这将增加
colorfulness of the subdued colors
柔和色彩的多姿多彩
okay i'm pretty happy with 43
好的 我对43号很满意
oh and a pro tip
哦 还有职业小费
always check your photo against the
一定要把你的照片与
white background from time to time you
白色背景时不时地让你
can always do that by clicking on the
可以随时通过单击
little light bulb icon at the bottom
底部的小灯泡图标
it looks like the photo is a bit too
看起来这张照片有点太大了
warm for my taste
对我来说很暖和
so i can always go back to color
这样我就可以随时回归色彩
calibration
定标
and reduce the temperature a tiny bit
把温度稍微降低一点
like so
就像这样
yeah i'm pretty happy with the results i
是的 我对结果很满意 我
think we managed to salvage the clipped
我想我们设法打捞到了被剪断的
areas and portray the brightness and the
区域 并描绘出亮度和
overall niceness of the weather of that
那里的天气总体上很好
day
天
awesome let's check that the output
太棒了 让我们检查一下输出
color profile is set to srgb and let's
颜色配置文件设置为sRGB 让我们
move back to light table
移回轻桌
in here i would like to introduce you to
在这里 我想向你们介绍
another feature
另一项功能
styles also known as presets
样式也称为预设
select an image you've already developed
选择您已开发的图像
and click create name your style
然后单击创建命名您的样式
i'll call it trip 1
我会把它称为旅行1
sunny
阳光充足的
and enable all the modules and their
并启用所有模块及其
settings you want transfer to other
您要转移到其他人的设置
photos
照片
modules like highlight reconstruction
高光重建等模块
which i have disabled
我已经禁用了它
exposure filmic rgb and color balance
曝光胶片RGB和色彩平衡
rgb and hit save now let's develop
RGB和Hit Save现在让我们开发
another photo that i took on the same
我在同一张照片上拍的另一张照片
day pretty much at the same spot but
一天几乎在同一地点 但
this time let's use the style that i've
这一次 让我们使用我的风格
just created to give us a nice baseline
刚刚为我们提供了一个很好的基线
i'll move back to darkroom
我要搬回暗室
i'll click on the styles icon and choose
我将单击样式图标并选择
the style i've just created
我刚刚创造的风格
that looks great already i would just
看起来已经很棒了 我只想
adjust the exposure a tiny bit
稍微调整一下曝光
and disable the reconstruction that
并禁用重建
we've done to the other photo
我们对另一张照片做了处理
simply by increasing the threshold
只需增加阈值即可
up to about four
最多大约四个人
you can always double click on the
您可以随时双击
slider to reset it to the default value
滑块将其重置为默认值
like so
就像这样
perfect
完美
back to light table we go
回到轻桌上 我们走
grab the two images we've just developed
抓起我们刚洗好的两张照片
and let's expand export section
让我们扩展一下出口部分
select the output folder
选择输出文件夹
select the format
选择格式
and resize if necessary i want the image
如果需要还可以调整大小我想要这张图片
to fit into 3000 by 3000 pixels
适合3000 x 3000像素
and hit export
并打击了出口
it will take a second or two
需要一两秒钟的时间
and your images are going to be ready if
如果你的照片已经准备好了
you're running windows 11 you can
您正在运行Windows 11 您可以
preview the files for the latest photos
预览文件以获取最新照片
app it works well and it's color managed
应用程序 它运行良好 并且进行了色彩管理
finally
终于到了
keep in mind that dark table will create
记住 黑暗的桌子会创造出
these sidecar xmp files
这些SideCar XMP文件
i recommend keeping them together with
我建议把它们放在一起
your camera native raw files
您的相机原生原始文件
as they store all the settings and
因为它们存储了所有的设置
tweaks we've done to the photo when we
我们对照片做的调整
developed it
将其发展
that's that we developed a few photos
我们拍了几张照片
using dark table
使用暗表
in this touristy tour bus manner
以这种旅游观光巴士的方式
i'd like to say a personal thank you to
我想对你说一句私人的感谢
aurelien pierre and his work on both
Aurelien Pierre和他的作品
dark table and youtube tutorials big
黑暗的桌子和YouTube教程大
thank you to troy sobotka as well and
也谢谢你特洛伊·索博特卡
his work educating their color curies i
他的工作教育他们的颜色居里
will link his scriptures in the
将他的经文链接到
description as well i hope i wasn't too
我也希望我不是太
boring and hope you learned something
无聊 希望你能学到一些东西
new today see you soon bye
新的今天再见